The Survey Corps left to
find a route to Zhiganshina,
but encountered an
intelligent Female Titan.
As soldiers died, one after the next,
they headed into a
forest of giant trees,
none of them knowing why.
If Squad Levi doesn't
defeat it, who will?
Another one's dead...
And maybe we could've saved him!
Choose.
Believe in yourself.
Or believe in the Survey Corps and me.
I'll go forward!
Fire!
He can't intend
to take that Titan alive?
Well, Eren? See that?
We caught that Titan!
This is the power of the Survey Corps!
Don't underestimate us, fool.
Well? Do you get it now?
Yes!
Looks like it's stopped moving...
We can't lower our guard.
But you did well, leading it here.
Men in the rearguard squads died
buying us the time we needed.
We couldn't have done it without them.
Is that so?
It is.
Thanks to them, we'll be able
to see who's inside this thing.
I hope they haven't pissed themselves...
Erwin Smith
57th Expedition Beyond the Walls (4)
An Aberrant?
Or is it like the Colossal Titan?
Did Commander Erwin...
Hey, snap out of it!
Eren, think later.
We need to get farther in and stand by!
Right!
Wait, Levi...
An eye for an eye.
Waves 2 and 3, fire!
Fire the spare rounds!
Um, it's climbing up...
Yeah.
If it gets this far, I'll
move out of the way.
But I don't think it will be long before
they issue withdrawal orders.
Does that have something
to do with the explosions
we've been hearing deep within the forest?
I don't know.
Mikasa, what do you think that sound is?
Are they firing cannons in the forest?
It didn't seem like they'd
brought cannons, though.
It's really loud back there.
Hey, Bertolt...
Do you know where Krista went?
Sorry, I don't know.
I have no idea what's going on.
What am I doing and why?
I want to go home.
We're going to shift position, Armin.
Okay.
They've started to figure it out.
They seem to keep getting better
and better at climbing.
That means, scary as it
sounds, they can learn.
Although some are better
than others, I'm sure.
Armin...
Sounds like something is going
on deeper in the forest.
I think I have some idea what.
They lured that Female Titan all the
way here in order to capture it.
More precisely...
To capture whoever is inside of it.
That was Commander Erwin's goal...
That was his plan from the very start!
Right?
I can see why he wouldn't
have told the new troops.
But why wouldn't he tell you
when you've all been with the
Survey Corps for so long?
Shut up!
Are you saying the Commander
and the Captain don't trust us?
But that's what this means...
Petra, rip out his teeth!
Swap the front and back teeth
when you shove 'em back in!
No, Eren's right.
I think there was a reason the
Commander couldn't trust us.
Like what?
There's only one reason he
wouldn't trust his fellow soldiers.
There's someone who can become a Titan,
or a spy helping them,
in the Survey Corps.
You think so, too, right?
It has to be one of us.
Yes, I think so.
A spy?
Is that possible?
At any rate, the Commander is certain.
I'd imagine the only soldiers who
were told of the plan were those
who've stayed alive for
the past five years.
I see...
So that's it.
Must be.
Understand, Eren?
That's why.
Yeah, if that's the
reason, I understand.
He's assuming that five years ago,
when the first wall fell,
a spy infiltrated our ranks...
And that's how he narrowed
down the possibilities.
Then, the spy killed Sawney and Bean?
Back then, the Commander
asked me about that.
What do you see?
What do you think the enemy is?
That's what the question meant?
If we could've answered it,
maybe we could've
participated in this plan.
I doubt that anyone could've
back then, though.
I knew.
But I didn't say anything.
Do you know why?
Why?
What, you can't tell?
Well, I shouldn't expect that
much from the likes of you.
You have yet to reach my level.
Hey, are you copying Captain Levi again?
The Captain wouldn't
say anything like that.
If this succeeds, I can get closer
to the truth of this world.
But... Too many died, regardless.
Do you think the Commander was wrong?
I can't say he was right.
If we'd known there was a Titan
informed of our operations,
we would've dealt with
this in a different way.
Your team's squad leader and
the others would've, too.
No, it wasn't wrong.
What wasn't wrong?
How many do you think
died for no reason?
Jean, after the fact, it's easy to say,
"We should've done something else."
However,
no one knows how things will turn out.
And even so, you have to make a choice.
You must.
The lives of a hundred
fellow soldiers...
Or the lives of all the humans
within the walls...
The Commander made his choice.
He chose to let those hundred die.
Eren, you don't know it yet,
but you will soon.
The reason that Erwin Smith is
entrusted with humanity's hope,
the Survey Corps.
Just look at how much
Captain Levi trusts him!
If you live that long...
I haven't lived that long,
but I'm certain of one thing.
If there's anyone who can bring change,
it will be someone willing to
sacrifice what they care for.
It will be someone who can throw aside
their humanity, in order
to defeat monsters.
Someone who can't sacrifice anything
can't ever change anything!
Information We Can Share So Far:
Special Target Capture Weapon (1)
A newly developed weapon the Survey Corps
created to capture a specific Titan.
Information We Can Share So Far:
Special Target Capture Weapon (2)
The barrels are loaded with seven steel tubes,
each of which has coiled wires with arrowheads at both ends.
Fire!
How do you like that?
You won't even be able
to scratch an itch now.
You won't be able to make a single move.
Probably for the rest of your life.
They're designed so that the
more you heal your wounds,
the more immobilized your joints become!
But they still can't draw
out whoever is inside?
What are Levi and Mike doing?
It can selectively harden its skin
to protect specific parts of its body?
It's similar to what I've
heard of the Armored Titan.
If we continue using the Maneuver
Gear and blades, will it weaken?
We don't have time to find out.
In that case...
Yes, sir?
Prepare the explosives.
Blow off its hands.
Yes, sir...
But there's a chance
that the amount we carry
has enough firepower to
also blow up what's inside.
Then set them to amputate the wrists.
Set them all off at once at my signal.
Roger.
Hey...
Why not just come out?
We don't have time to waste.
So...
What do you think will
happen to you now?
Do you believe you can escape?
I wish you'd consider all the
trouble we're going through...
As I recall, you killed
my troops in various ways.
Did you find it fun?
Right now, I'm having fun.
Well, so are you, right?
I think you can understand me.
Oh, right...
I wanted to ask you something.
Is it okay if we cut off
your hands and legs?
They'll grow back, right?
I'm talking about your
limbs, not the Titan's.
We need you alive, after all...
Well, that was a surprise.
Were those her dying screams?
Erwin, it stinks.
What direction?
Multiple sources, from
all directions at once.
What's up with them?
They're all running into the forest?
Why did they suddenly start ignoring us?
What?
They're all Aberrants?
It doesn't matter!
Don't let them through!
Begin combat!
What just happened?
Wait...
I've heard that scream before.
In the forests where I'm from...
It's the cry of a cornered animal
that has nothing to lose!
I was taught to exercise greater caution
once a hunt drew to a close!
So be careful?
A hundred times more than usual!
If you underestimate
the forest, you'll die!
I grew up in the mountains, too.
Someone who grew crops
wouldn't understand!
I see.
It's true that Sasha's
intuition is usually good.
Especially when she predicts
things are going sour.
Armin thought Eren would be in
the center, toward the rear...
Ready those explosives, now!
Erwin...
The first wave will come from the east.
They're almost here.
Cart guard team, intercept!
They ignored us?
Are they Aberrants?
Three are breaking through!
Captain Levi!
You just did something,
didn't you, bitch?
So they're after the Female Titan?
Titans from all directions!
All men, engage.
Defend the Female Titan,
even if it means your lives!
It's no use!
Retreat, men!
Back into formation!
Return to Karanes!
We've been had.
Just look at you.
Don't tell me...
The enemy
was willing to sacrifice everything.
I didn't expect the enemy to destroy
itself along with the evidence
by making Titans devour itself.
All our talk at the court martial,
and this is what happens.
If we return empty-handed, who knows
what will happen to Eren or us.
We can think about that after we return.
Our priority now is getting home
without additional casualties.
For now...
The steam from the corpse is limiting visibility.
It could interfere with our signal
flare message relay system.
I'll call my team.
Wait, Levi...
Refill your gas and blades.
There isn't time.
I think I have plenty.
Why?
That's an order.
Follow it.
Roger, Erwin.
I trust your decision.
We're retreating.
Everyone, retreat.
Get back on your horse, and retreat.
Right!
What? It's already over?
We can go home! All right!
What's going on?
Where's Eren?
Looks like it's over.
Back to the horses! Prepare to retreat!
You heard the man...
Let's go see what the
bastard inside looks like.
Will we really find out who it is?
It's thanks to you.
I didn't really do anything.
You had faith in us.
This is the result of your choice
to trust us back then.
Making the right choice isn't easy.
Hey, don't spoil him, Petra...
What did he do, anyway?
He was pathetic. He just kept whining.
Well, coming back alive on your
first excursion is pretty good.
But it doesn't count
until the mission's over.
Listen, kiddo, the expedition lasts
until you're at home in bed...
Jeez, I know that!
Oluo! Petra!
You guys pissed your pants and
cried on your first mission.
You're all grown up now!
Don't say that!
What if he stops respecting me?!
It's true?
It sure is.
And I didn't, by the way, Eren.
Idiot!
I've killed more of them than you!
More of them than you, idiot!
Kill count isn't all
that makes a soldier.
Shut up, idiot!
Petra...
Does that mean you sprayed
it everywhere while mid-air?
Shut up!
Do you think you're on a picnic?
We're outside the walls!
I didn't piss my pants, either, Eren.
Oh, I'm sure that's the
signal from Captain Levi.
We'll rendezvous with the Captain!
Cut the chatter till we get back.
Erwin...
Why did you order Levi to resupply?
There's no time to waste.
The Female Titan was eaten.
But did you see the
person inside get eaten?
I didn't.
You can't mean...
Yes...
If your original hypothesis was correct,
and they can still move to a degree
after regaining human form...
And if they'd equipped
Maneuver Gear in advance...
The one within the Female Titan
is wearing our uniform right now.
Captain Levi?
No, it's not!
Who are you?!
G-Gunther!
What? Why?
Gunther!
The enemy is now camouflaged
as one of our men.
The capture operation has failed.
The Female Titan appears
before Eren once more.
What stands between it and its target
are the master Titan killers,
the Special Ops Squad.
Crushing Blow
57th Expedition Beyond the Walls (5)